The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: It's a bit better, my heart's back in place.
教授：好多了，我的心脏恢复了原状。
I'm glad that not everyone's gone.
我很高兴不是每个人都走了。
AUDIENCE: Well you mean passed out and died from the test?
听众：你是说通过考试而死了吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: OK, no there were a few students left.
听众：好吧，没有剩下几个学生了。
PROFESSOR: That's good, that's good.
教授：很好，很好。
I think once we release the results everyone will calm
我认为一旦发布结果，每个人都会平静
down, and we'll realize that the mistake was on our part.
下来，我们会意识到错误是我们的责任。
AUDIENCE: The mistake?
听众：错了吗？
PROFESSOR: I mean the results are lower than what we thought.
教授：我的意思是结果比我们想象的要低。
And it's because we haven't covered something
这是因为我们还没有涵盖
that I will cover today.
我今天将介绍。
So we think-- well we talked about it yesterday,
所以我们认为-好，我们昨天讨论过这个问题，
and we think we haven't done enough algorithm
而且我们认为我们还没有完成足够的算法
design with you guys.
与你们一起设计。
So today I have problems, and we're
所以今天我有问题，我们
going to come up with solutions.
将提出解决方案。
AUDIENCE: Are you not going to tell us
听众：你不想告诉我们吗
what [INAUDIBLE] number is?
什么是[音频不清晰]？
PROFESSOR: It's in the lecture notes.
教授：在讲义中。
It's actually quite boring.
这实际上很无聊。
I promise it's really boring.
我保证这真的很无聊。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: And if you want to do that next time when
教授：如果您下次想做
we'll actually talk about numerics.
我们实际上将讨论数字。
The thing is numerics are straightforward.
关键是数字很简单。
Once you learn the algorithms you're
学习算法之后，
not going to come up with a new one.
不会提出一个新的。
I'm pretty sure about that.
我对此很确定。
Like you're not going to come up with a revolutionary way
就像你不会想出一种革命性的方式
of adding two numbers.
两个数之和。
AUDIENCE: I don't know.
听众：我不知道。
You never know.
你永远都不会知道。
PROFESSOR: Well you can tell me why.
教授：好吧，你可以告诉我为什么。
Think about it and then you can tell me
考虑一下，然后你可以告诉我
why you are not going to.
为什么你不去。
AUDIENCE: OK, got it.
听众：知道了。
PROFESSOR: OK so let's start with a problem.
教授：好的，让我们开始一个问题。
We know what sorted arrays look like, right?
我们知道排序后的数组是什么样的，对吧？
1, 3, 5, 6, 7, 9, 12.
1、3、5、6、7、9、12
This is a sorted array.
这是一个排序的数组。
If we're given a sorted array we know
如果我们得到一个排序的数组，我们知道
how to find the number in it, right?
如何找到其中的号码，对不对？
What's the running time for that.
这是什么时间？
AUDIENCE: For any given number?
听众：对于任何给定的数字？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Well what's the best way that we know?
教授：那么，我们所知道的最好的方法是什么？
AUDIENCE: Logarithm.
听众：对数。
PROFESSOR: Log and binary search, right?
教授：日志和二进制搜索，对吗？
Well instead of this we're given a shifted array.
好吧，我们得到的是移位数组。
And shifted means that-- say you're
转移意味着-你在
shifting the array by K elements.
将数组移动K个元素。
We're taking these guys.
我们要带这些家伙。
So the array is shifted to the left.
因此，数组向左移动。
So these K elements end up on the right.
因此，这些K元素最终出现在右侧。
These N minus K elements end up on the left.
这些N减K元素最后出现在左侧。
So 7, 9, 12, 1, 3, 5, 6.
所以7、9、12、1、3、5、6
So still N elements they are shifted by some number K.
因此，N个元素仍然偏移了K个数。
And I want to find one number, e, in the array.
我想在数组中找到一个数字e。
I don't know K by the way.
顺便说一下，我不知道K。
We just know that it's a shifted array.
我们只知道这是一个移位数组。
This is 12.
12岁
So the first thing you do is figure out
所以你要做的第一件事就是弄清楚
how much time you have for this, right?
你有多少时间，对吗？
If you're on a test, you roughly know how much time
如果您正在测试中，您大概会知道多少时间
you have for a problem.
你有问题。
If you're on an interview you have
如果您正在面试中
to figure out how much time the interviewer is
找出面试官多少时间
willing to give you for problem.
愿意给您解决问题。
And spend the first, I don't, a third
并花第一，我不花第三
of the time thinking maybe.
也许是时候想
Come up with the best solution that you can.
提出最好的解决方案。
And then stop there, and start talking.
然后停在那里，开始交谈。
So the first thing you do, you want
所以你要做的第一件事就是
to make sure that when you run out of time
确保您用完时间
you have something to say.
你有话要说。
The most awful thing you can say is, dude I'm going home now.
您能说的最糟糕的是，伙计，我现在要回家。
Or leave the answer blank.
或将答案留空。
If you leave the answer blank we're
如果您将答案留空，我们就是
not going to give you points, right?
不会给你分数，对吗？
So not good.
不好
So what's the worst answer you could give us?
那么，您能给我们的最糟糕的答案是什么？
OK worst is a bad term.
好的，最糟糕的是一个坏词。
What's the brute force solution to this?
什么是强力解决方案？
The solution where we don't care about the running time,
我们不在乎运行时间的解决方案，
but we want the correct answer.
但是我们想要正确的答案。
AUDIENCE: Look everywhere.
听众：随处可见。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So do a linear search.
因此进行线性搜索。
Pretend we don't know anything about this array.
假装我们对此数组一无所知。
Lose the information that it's a shifted array.
丢失了它是移位数组的信息。
Linear search running time order N.
线性搜索运行时间顺序N。
OK so this is something, at least now
好，至少现在是这样
when your time runs out you have something.
当您的时间用完时，您会有一些东西。
You're not going to leave empty handed.
您不会无所事事。
Let's start thinking now.
让我们现在开始思考。
Next step.
下一步。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] can we shift it again?
听众：[听不清]我们可以再改变一次吗？
PROFESSOR: So the fact that it's shifted
教授：所以事实已经转移了
means that-- so originally it was sorted, right?
就是说-最初是对它进行排序的，对吗？
But now instead of it being completely sorted,
但是现在，它没有被完全分类，
you have all the elements are shifted to the left.
您已将所有元素移到左侧。
And then so there's a rotation thing going on here.
然后，这里发生了旋转。
So these elements got out of the array
所以这些元素脱离了数组
and then they are put back in from the other side.
然后将它们从另一侧放回去。
AUDIENCE: Why do we do that?
听众：我们为什么要这样做？
PROFESSOR: That's how the info looks like.
教授：这就是信息的样子。
We don't do it.
我们不这样做。
It was done to us.
它已经完成了。
AUDIENCE: Oh OK.
听众：好的。
So now what do we want?
那么，现在我们想要什么？
PROFESSOR: We want to find an element--
教授：我们想找到一个元素-
AUDIENCE: Oh, I see.
听众：哦，我知道了。
PROFESSOR: --despite the fact that the array looks like this.
教授：-尽管数组看起来像这样。
AUDIENCE: Do we know that the list that we have
观众：我们知道我们拥有的清单吗？
is shifted already?
已经转移了吗？
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
So we're promised that this is a shifted array.
因此，我们保证这是一个移位数组。
So it will look like this.
因此它将看起来像这样。
But we don't know what K is.
但是我们不知道K是什么。
If we knew what K is, could we do something fast?
如果我们知道K是多少，我们可以快速做点什么吗？
What would we do?
我们会怎么做？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, you'd just re-shift [INAUDIBLE].
听众：是的，您只需要重新安排[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: OK so if you re-shifted
教授：好的，所以如果您重新上班
what's the running time?
几点钟了？
AUDIENCE: For order K [INAUDIBLE].
听众：对于订单K [听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK so if we actually shifted
教授：好的，所以如果我们真的转移了
and then do a binary search it's order K plus log
然后执行二进制搜索，顺序为K加对数
N. So for big K's that's not better.
N.所以对于大K来说，这并不更好。
AUDIENCE: Why is it not order N plus log [INAUDIBLE].
听众：为什么不订购N加日志[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: You can say that since we don't have any promise
教授：您可以这样说，因为我们没有任何承诺
on K it's N. It's order K if you can shift things out of both
在K上是N。如果可以将两者都移出，则是K阶
N's.
N的。
With Python this would be order N,
使用Python，这将是N阶
just popping out one element is order N in Python.
仅弹出一个元素就是Python中的N阶。
So this is assuming a smart array.
因此，这是一个智能阵列。
Otherwise if it's Python, good point.
否则，如果是Python，那就好了。
It's straight up order N. So now another good point.
它是顺序N。所以现在是另一个好处。
You have this solution, and you have the brute force solution.
您拥有此解决方案，并且拥有蛮力解决方案。
They have the same running time.
它们具有相同的运行时间。
You run out of time.
您时间用完了。
Which one are you going to code up?
您要编写哪一个？
Which one are you going to show?
您要显示哪一个？
AUDIENCE: The simpler one.
听众：比较简单。
PROFESSOR: The simpler one, excellent.
教授：简单一点，很棒。
So the reason is, if you're on a test
所以原因是，如果您正在测试
it's probably give the pseudocode, then analyze it.
它可能会给出伪代码，然后对其进行分析。
If you're in an interview the guy will ask you OK,
如果您正在面试中，那家伙会问您好，
what's the running time?
几点钟了？
Code it up on the board in C, Java, whatever he knows.
不管他知道什么，都可以用C，Java在板上编写代码。
So you want to code the simplest solution,
因此，您想编写最简单的解决方案，
because that reduces the chance that you'll have bugs.
因为这样可以减少出现错误的机会。
So that gives you the most points.
这样可以给您最多的积分。
So this solution shows more insight,
因此，此解决方案显示出更多的见解，
but it doesn't have a better run time.
但它没有更好的运行时间。
Stick to the simple solution.
坚持简单的解决方案。
However if you have this then you
但是，如果你有这个，那你
have some insight on the problem.
对这个问题有一些见识。
So you can keep going and hope you
所以你可以继续并希望你
can come up with a better answer.
可以提出一个更好的答案。
So if we knew K, one thing we could do
因此，如果我们知道K，我们可以做一件事
is reduce the array to an unshifted array.
将数组简化为未移动的数组。
What's another thing we can do?
我们还能做什么？
So I claim that if you know K you
所以我声称如果你知道K
can come up with a reasonably easy log N method.
可以提出一个相当简单的log N方法。
AUDIENCE: If you're doing binary search,
听众：如果您正在执行二进制搜索，
like if you just pretend like the array is all together,
就像假装数组一样
but if you know K. So let's say you're looking for 6.
但是如果您知道K。那么假设您正在寻找6。
Then you'd say oh well I'm going to split the array half,
然后你会说，哦，好吧，我将阵列拆分一半，
but you're actually going to start at K
但实际上您将从K开始
and then split it in half.
然后将其分成两半。
So it's like you pretend that--
就像你假装那样
PROFESSOR: So what you want to say
教授：那么你想说什么
is you have a pretend array in your mind, right?
你脑子里有假装吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
It's [INAUDIBLE] by K.
是K [听不清]。
PROFESSOR: And you want to access the middle element
教授：您想访问中间元素
to see if what you're looking for is bigger or smaller.
看看您要寻找的是更大还是更小。
Instead of looking at the middle element here,
而不是在这里看中间的元素，
you look at the middle plus K, right?
你看中间加K，对不对？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
Oh, there you go.
哦，你去。
Plus K.
加K。
PROFESSOR: This is one way of doing it, good running time.
教授：这是一种实现方法，可以延长运行时间。
The problem is it's hard.
问题是很难。
You'll have to rewrite binary search and hope it works.
您将不得不重写二进制搜索，并希望它能工作。
What I would do, given that I've had
考虑到我曾经做过的事
a bit of time to think about it, is this is sorted.
需要一点时间考虑一下，这是排序的。
This is sorted.
这是排序的。
So two binary searched are also going to be log N time.
因此，两个二进制搜索的时间也将是N次。
Two binary searches, two lines of pseudocode.
两个二进制搜索，两行伪代码。
The running time analysis is pretty simple.
运行时间分析非常简单。
Correctness is also pretty simple.
正确性也很简单。
And also this gives me some insight
这也给我一些见识
on the rest of the problem I claim.
关于我声称的其余问题。
OK so if we have K we can do log N. What if we don't have K?
好的，所以如果我们有K，我们可以记录N。如果没有K，该怎么办？
What do we do?
我们做什么？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Figure out what K is.
听众：找出K是什么。
PROFESSOR: All right let's try to find K. We know how to do it
教授：好的，让我们尝试找到K。我们知道该怎么做
if we have K. So let's try to find K. What-- if I want
如果我们有K，那么让我们尝试找到K。
to arrive to a solution that's log N,
到达记录为N的解决方案，
how much time can I spend on finding K?
我可以花多少时间找到K？
OK so let's find K in log N time.
好的，让我们在N次日志中找到K。
AUDIENCE: Binary search for minimum?
听众：二进制搜索的最小值？
PROFESSOR: Binary search-- so I like binary search,
教授：二进制搜索-所以我喜欢二进制搜索，
because binary search is an algorithm that
因为二进制搜索是一种算法
runs on an array.
在数组上运行。
And that runs in log N time.
并以N倍的时间运行。
So if I'm able to make it work I know everything's
因此，如果我能够使其正常工作，我就会知道一切
going to be right in terms of time.
在时间方面将是正确的。
So what do you run a binary search for?
那么，您要执行二进制搜索吗？
AUDIENCE: The smallest number possible?
听众：可能的最小数目？
I guess that's kind of going through all of them, though.
不过，我想所有这些都会经历。
It doesn't really help.
它并没有真正的帮助。
PROFESSOR: So if you have the min.
教授：所以，如果您愿意。
Sorry, you can speak in one second.
抱歉，您可以在一秒钟内说出来。
AUDIENCE: Oh we have the min!
听众：哦，我们有分钟！
PROFESSOR: So no, if you can't have the min.
教授：所以，如果您没有时间的话。
I think it's good insight.
我认为这是很好的见解。
So if you knew where the min is, you know this is K, right?
所以，如果您知道最小值在哪里，那么您知道这是K，对吧？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So this is the minimum,
教授：这是最低要求，
that's K. OK, what were you going to say?
那是K。好的，你要说什么？
AUDIENCE: Oh for just binary search
听众：哦，仅是二进制搜索
it would not [INAUDIBLE] minimum.
它不会[听不清]最小值。
I was thinking that if we start at 1 we will see to our right
我在想，如果我们从1开始，我们会看到右边的
and left.
离开。
And the point where [INAUDIBLE] are ending
还有[听不清]的结尾
is where we have something larger to our right
是我们右边更大的地方
and something smaller to our left.
还有一些在我们左边的东西。
PROFESSOR: OK so there's a discontinuity here,
教授：好的，所以这里不连续，
that's what you're saying, right?
那就是你的意思，对吧？
So this is sorted.
所以这是排序。
But then at this point this breaks.
但是在这一点上，这打破了。
AUDIENCE: Yes, we are kind of finding that point where
听众：是的，我们有点发现
something to the right that's greater
右边的东西更大
than [INAUDIBLE] and something to the left
比[听不清]和左边的东西
is also greater than [INAUDIBLE].
也大于[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: OK so let's see if we can do that.
教授：好的，让我们看看是否可以这样做。
So for binary search you have to go somewhere.
因此，对于二进制搜索，您必须去某个地方。
So in our case we're trying to get K, right?
所以在我们的情况下，我们试图获得K，对不对？
And we know that it's somewhere between 1 and 10.
而且我们知道它在1到10之间。
And what binary search does is it makes a guess.
二进制搜索的作用是猜测。
It says hey, I think it's in the middle of the array.
它说，嘿，我认为它位于数组的中间。
So it will probably guess n over 2.
因此，它可能会猜测n大于2。
And it makes a guess and you have
它可以猜测，你有
to tell it was the guess too small,
告诉我猜测太小了，
or was the guess too large?
还是猜测太大？
Because this is what allows you to recurse
因为这使您可以递归
on either the left interval or on the right interval.
在左间隔或右间隔上。
The problem with a discontinuity is, if I guess here,
如果我猜这里，不连续性的问题是
and if I guess here, I still don't see the discontinuity.
如果我猜在这里，我仍然看不到间断。
So it's good inside, but it's not enough.
因此，内部效果不错，但还不够。
I need a little bit more.
我还需要一点。
Yes, 2, 3 hands oh wow you guys don't got it?
是的，有2、3手哦，你们没有吗？
AUDIENCE: So I think we can arbitrarily
听众：所以我认为我们可以随心所欲
take the halfway point instead of subtracting
取中点而不是减去
from the first element.
从第一个元素开始。
And then if it's a negative number,
然后如果它是负数，
then discontinuity will be in this half.
那么间断将在这一半。
If it's [INAUDIBLE] it will be in the other half.
如果它是[音频不清晰]，则将在另一半。
And then you recurse on that.
然后您对此进行递归。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So let's draw this up.
因此，让我们草拟一下。
So in a sorted array the numbers look like this.
因此，在排序数组中，数字看起来像这样。
In a shifted array we splice it here,
在一个移位数组中，我们将其拼接在这里，
and this guy goes to the right.
这个家伙走到右边
So it's like this and then like this.
就是这样，然后这样。
So this picture shows me the insight that I had before,
所以这张照片向我展示了我以前的见识，
that this part is sorted and this part is sorted.
该部分已排序，该部分已排序。
The missing part, which I just heard now,
我刚才听到的缺失部分
is that since the whole array was originally sorted,
是因为整个数组最初都是经过排序的，
this guy is smaller than this guy.
这个家伙比这个家伙小。
So if I draw a horizontal line here,
所以如果我在这里画一条水平线，
I can draw a horizontal line somewhere,
我可以在某处画一条水平线，
and this and this will not cross it.
而这并不会越过它。
So this whole thing is taller than this.
所以这件事比这更高。
So by the way, K was where the discontinuity was, right?
顺便说一下，K是不连续的地方，对不对？
You said discontinuity.
你说不连续
This is K, it's somewhere here.
这是K，在这里。
So this is a better.
因此，这是一个更好的选择。
So if I make my guess and I land somewhere here,
所以，如果我猜对了，然后降落在这里，
I can know that my guess is too big,
我知道我的猜测太大了
because it's below the line.
因为它在线下
If I make my guess and it's somewhere here,
如果我猜到了，就在这里
I know my guess is too small, because the number that I
我知道我的猜测太小了，因为我的数字
see here is above the line.
看到这里是线上方。
Who sets the line?
谁来打线？
The first element here.
这里的第一个元素。
So this is how you look at it graphically.
这就是您以图形方式查看它的方式。
If you don't want to look at it graphically,
如果您不想以图形方式查看它，
this was a sorted array.
这是一个排序的数组。
If this is the Kth element, then everything
如果这是第K个元素，那么一切
here is smaller than it.
这里比它小。
So all these guys are smaller than the first element.
因此，所有这些家伙都比第一个元素小。
OK so honestly who understands the solution?
好吧，老实说，谁知道解决方案？
3, 4, OK.
3、4
Oh, OK pretty good.
哦，还不错。
Do we want to code this up, or do we
我们是否要对此进行编码，还是我们
want to look at another problem?
想看看另一个问题？
OK who wants to look at another problem?
好，谁想看看另一个问题？
Clear majority, all right.
清楚多数，好的。
Usually I have to do both choices,
通常我必须同时做两个选择
because not enough people are paying attention to get this.
因为没有足够的人关注这一点。
So I am happy.
所以我很高兴。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
All right so before I start another problem, one thing
好吧，在我开始另一个问题之前，一件事
I want to say.
我想说。
Not only do I have a solution for this problem,
我不仅有解决这个问题的方法，
but I have a process that allowed
但是我有一个允许的过程
me to go from nothing to a few partial solutions.
我从一无所有到一些部分解决方案。
And while I was doing that, I was getting insight
当我这样做的时候，我正在获得洞察力
and I was making sure that if I run out of time before I have
并且我确保如果我没时间用完之前
the final solution, I don't walk out of the room empty handed.
最终的解决方案，我不会空着手走出房间。
So I don't just want to show you the final solution,
因此，我不仅要向您展示最终解决方案，
I want to show you the process.
我想告诉你这个过程。
You can look at the notes and see the final solution.
您可以查看注释并查看最终解决方案。
That's not everything I want you to get out of this.
那不是我想要您摆脱的一切。
OK, problem 2 has a heap.
好的，问题2有堆。
And this is a minimum heap, so it looks like this.
这是最小堆，所以看起来像这样。
So this is a minimum heap, N elements.
所以这是一个最小的堆，N个元素。
And I want to extract the kth smallest element in the heap.
我想提取堆中第k个最小的元素。
So if K equals 3, this is the third smallest element, right?
因此，如果K等于3，这是第三小的元素，对吗？
K equals 4, it's this guy.
K等于4，就是这个人。
5, and 6, 1 and 2 are here.
5、6、1和2在这里。
OK the good running time that we want,
确定我们想要的良好运行时间，
because this is a hard problem so we give you
因为这是一个难题，所以我们给你
the running time, is K log K. However
运行时间是K logK。但是
before we do that I want to hear some brute force solutions.
在我们这样做之前，我想听听一些暴力解决方案。
AUDIENCE: All of them.
听众：全部。
PROFESSOR: And?
教授：还有？
OK you need to sort them first.
确定，您需要先对其进行排序。
So this heap is actually an array, right?
所以这个堆实际上是一个数组，对吗？
2, 5, 7, 6, 8, oh it's 6, 9, 8, sorry.
2、5、7、6、8，哦，是6、9、8，对不起。
So you're saying sort the array, then K--
所以您说的是对数组进行排序，然后是K--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK what's the running time for this?
教授：好的，这是什么时间？
AUDIENCE: Log N.
听众：登录N。
PROFESSOR: All right we have a solution.
教授：好的，我们有一个解决方案。
We're not going to leave empty handed.
我们不会空手而归。
OK let's try to go a bit better.
好吧，让我们尝试更好一些。
What's another way of going it that'll
这样做的另一种方式是
give me a better running time?
给我更好的跑步时间？
AUDIENCE: You could pop 5 of the K elements off of the--
听众：您可以从以下位置弹出K个元素中的5个：
PROFESSOR: All right so this is a mean heap, right?
教授：好的，所以这是一个卑鄙的堆吧？
So it has find min.
所以它找到分钟。
And find min runs in order log N. So if I call it K times
并找到最小运行顺序日志N。因此，如果我将其称为K次
I'm going to get the K smallest elements.
我将获得K个最小的元素。
By the way heap sort says pop and times,
顺便说一句，堆排序说明了流行音乐和时代，
and you'll have all the elements in sorted order.
您将拥有所有元素的排序顺序。
So we're doing a heap sort, except we
因此，我们正在进行堆排序，除了
stop when we lose interest after K elements.
当我们失去对K个元素的兴趣后，停止。
So we're down from N log N to K log N.
所以我们从N log N降到K logN。
So I would be interested in hearing a solution that's
所以我有兴趣听到一个解决方案
worse, because it would look like N log K.
更糟的是，因为它看起来像N logK。
But shows me more insight.
但是显示了我更多的见识。
So by the way this is good.
因此，这很好。
You're already K log N. So K log N, the correct answer
您已经是K logN。所以，K log N是正确的答案
is K log K. Small difference, right?
是K logK。差异很小，对不对？
It's a logarithm factor.
这是一个对数因子。
At least it's not an N factor.
至少这不是一个N因素。
If you code this up chances are we're
如果您对此进行编码，那么我们是
not going to be able to distinguish between this.
无法区分这两者。
So you'll never see this on a PSet.
因此，您将永远不会在PSet上看到它。
So you're almost there.
所以你快到了。
And this is just applying straight up knowledge
这只是应用直接的知识
that we had before.
我们以前有过的。
Let's look at this solution, if anyone sees it.
让我们看看这个解决方案，如果有人看到的话。
Before we attempt K log K.
在我们尝试K log K之前。
AUDIENCE: In another case would we
听众：在另一种情况下，我们会
just pop off first K elements, why would that be in log N?
只是弹出第一个K元素，为什么会在日志N中？
Because it's actually an array, so I
因为它实际上是一个数组，所以我
would think that we'd just take the K time.
会以为我们会花K时间。
PROFESSOR: So this is a heap.
教授：这是一堆。
If you don't maintain the heaping variant
如果您不维护堆变体
after you do the first pop you're
完成第一个流行音乐之后，
not going to be able to do the second one.
不能去做第二个。
OK, cool.
好的。
So let me give you a hint.
让我给你一个提示。
How would we find-- if this is an array--
我们如何找到-如果这是一个数组-
how do I find the minimum?
我如何找到最低要求？
2, 5, 7, did I forget something?
2、5、7，我忘了什么吗？
No.
没有。
Let's pretend this array doesn't start with 2, because it's
我们假设这个数组不是以2开头的，因为它是
boring if it starts with 2.
如果从2开始则很无聊。
How do I find the minimum?
我如何找到最低要求？
I keep one variable that says the best I've seen so far,
我保留了一个变量，该变量表示到目前为止我所见过的最好的变量，
right?
对？
Let's see, N-- oh this is still boring.
让我们看看，N-噢，这仍然很无聊。
Let's start here.
让我们从这里开始。
So we start with best seen equals 7.
因此，我们从最佳观看次数等于7开始。
Then when we go to 6 we see, is 6 better than best seen?
然后，当我们转到6时，我们看到的6比最佳视点好吗？
If so, replace best seen with 6.
如果是这样，请用6代替最佳显示。
If not keep going.
如果不能继续前进。
Then I get to 9.
然后我到达9。
Is 9 better than best seen?
9比最佳影片好吗？
Nope, keep going.
不，继续前进。
Is 8 better than best seen?
8比最佳影片好吗？
Nope, keep going.
不，继续前进。
So I compare every element with the best seen,
因此，我将每个元素与最明显的元素进行比较，
and then whenever the element is better I do a replacement.
然后只要元素更好，我都会进行替换。
And then at the end, best seen will have the smallest element.
最后，最好看的元素将最小。
So this algorithm works for k equals
所以这个算法适用于k个等于
1, which isn't very useful.
1，不是很有用。
So can we generalize this somehow
那么我们可以以某种方式将其概括吗
to-- so we have a running time here.
到-因此我们在这里有一个运行时间。
That might give you a hint about how we want to generalize it,
这可能会给您一些提示，说明我们如何将其概括化，
and I want to generalize it for all values of K.
我想对K的所有值进行归纳。
AUDIENCE: If you go to the power of 2 then it's less than--
听众：如果您使用2的幂，则小于-
the nearest power of 2 less than K--
小于2的最接近的幂-
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: --that element, and iterate forward with your best
听众：-该元素，并尽力而为
seen.
看过。
Does that make sense?
那有意义吗？
If you want the kth, if you want the tenth smallest element,
如果想要第k个元素，如果想要第10个最小元素，
then it has to be after the 8th row
那么它必须在第八行之后
because it's the next level in the tree.
因为它是树中的下一层。
Does that make sense?
那有意义吗？
That doesn't make sense.
那没有道理。
PROFESSOR: It makes sense, but I don't think it's right.
教授：这是有道理的，但我认为这是不对的。
So you're thinking that the tenth smallest element
所以您认为第十个最小元素
has to be somewhere below, right?
必须在下面某处吧？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, and then pretend
教授：1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9、10，然后假装
that there are numbers here.
这里有数字。
11, 12, 13, 14, 15, do you see what I'm saying?
11，12，13，14，15，您明白我在说什么吗？
So this is a heap.
所以这是一个堆。
So I can keep filling it with bigger elements,
所以我可以继续用更大的元素填充它，
and 10 is here.
还有十个在这里
However you can do something else
但是你可以做点别的
to limit the size of the heap.
限制堆的大小。
It will give us a different running time,
它将为我们提供不同的运行时间，
but you can do something.
但是你可以做点什么。
You can think about it.
您可以考虑一下。
How can you chop up some of the heap?
您如何切碎一些堆？
For example if I have a heap that's ten deep
例如，如果我有一个十深的堆
and I look at the fourth element, what can I do?
我看第四个要素，我该怎么办？
You can think about that.
您可以考虑一下。
And let's try to get to this.
让我们尝试着做到这一点。
So I'll accept an answer for either
所以我会接受一个答案
how do we limit the heap in that case,
在这种情况下，我们如何限制堆，
or how do we generalize this algorithm.
或如何概括该算法。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: You want us to remember the smallest K
听众：您希望我们记住最小的K
elements, you'd make a max heap [INAUDIBLE] K [INAUDIBLE]
元素，您将创建一个最大堆[音频不清晰] K [音频不清晰]
[INAUDIBLE].
[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK so I want to have--
教授：好的，我想...
I'll break down your solution into parts .
我将把您的解决方案分成几部分。
So you want to have a bag of the smallest K elements, right?
因此，您想要一袋最小的K元素，对吗？
So instead of the best seen, you want to have the K best seen.
因此，您希望让K最好的显示，而不是最佳的显示。
And once you have a bag you want to go through your elements.
一旦有了一个包，您就想要遍历所有元素。
And then if you have something that's
然后如果你有一些东西
better than what you have in the bag,
比你的书包要好
you want to put that in the bag.
你想把它放在袋子里。
Suppose I have, suppose K equals 3,
假设我有，假设K等于3，
and I have 2, 5, and 7 in the bag.
我的书包里有2、5和7。
And I see 6.
我看到了6。
Who do I want to compare it with?
我想和谁比较？
The biggest thing in the bag, right?
包里最大的东西，对吧？
So if I want the K smallest elements,
因此，如果我想要K个最小的元素，
if this guy is smaller than anything,
如果这个家伙比什么都小，
these aren't the K smallest elements anymore.
这些不再是K个最小的元素了。
So I want to take the maximum in the bag,
所以我想拿最大的东西，
compare it with what I'm seeing right now,
将其与我现在所看到的进行比较，
and if what I'm seeing is smaller I want to replace it.
如果我看到的尺寸较小，我想更换它。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Because I keep doing this maximum,
教授：因为我一直在努力，
I keep asking this maximum question,
我一直在问这个最大的问题，
this has to be a max heap.
这必须是最大堆。
That's why he said max heap.
这就是为什么他说最大堆。
So you did all these steps at once
所以您一次完成所有这些步骤
and then gave me the final answer.
然后给了我最后的答案。
But this is how you do it step by step.
但这是您逐步执行的方法。
So it looks like finding the minimum element,
所以看起来就像找到最小元素，
except you have a bag.
除了你有一个袋子。
And that bag has to be a maximum heap.
而且那个袋子必须是最大的堆。
And the original heap is a minimum heap.
并且原始堆是最小堆。
So the fact that you have to use a maximum heap
因此，您必须使用最大堆的事实
is a bit nontrivial.
有点平凡。
Good answer.
好答案。
All right so we have K log N, and we
好吧，我们有K log N，我们
have N log K, so choose what you want to have in your log.
拥有N个日志K，因此请选择您要在日志中包含的内容。
We have a solution for you.
我们为您提供解决方案。
How about this.
这个怎么样。
How are we doing here?
我们在这里怎么样？
So suppose I'm looking for the fourth element,
因此，假设我正在寻找第四个要素，
and my heap has 10 levels.
我的堆有10个关卡
How can I chop it-- how can I reduce
我怎么砍-我怎么减少
the number of things I'm looking at?
我正在看的东西数量是多少？
AUDIENCE: You can reduce it down to 4 levels.
听众：您可以将其降低到4级。
PROFESSOR: I can reduce it down to 4 levels, exactly.
教授：我可以将其降低到4级。
So this heap has log N levels.
因此，此堆具有N个日志级别。
And my K is smaller than log N. I can reduce the heap down
我的K小于对数N。我可以减少堆空间
to K levels and discard everything below.
到K级并丢弃下面的所有内容。
And the reason for that is we have a mean heap, right?
究其原因，是因为我们有一个堆，对吗？
So if we go down from, on any path from the roots to a leaf,
因此，如果我们从根部到叶子的任何路径下来，
the values have to increase, right?
价值必须增加，对吗？
Otherwise it's not a mean keep.
否则，这不是刻薄的。
Otherwise there's an invariant violation somewhere there.
否则，那里某个地方会有一个不变的违规行为。
So as I go down on any path my numbers are going up.
所以当我沿着任何一条路走下去时，我的数字都在上升。
So these are all the paths of length 4.
这些都是长度为4的路径。
All of them have to go through here.
他们都必须经过这里。
All the paths of length 4 will stop here.
所有长度为4的路径都将在此处停止。
So I know that everything here has
所以我知道这里的一切都有
to be bigger than the first 4 elements.
大于前四个元素。
So if I reduce this to K and I discard everything else,
因此，如果我将其减少为K并丢弃其他所有内容，
what's the running time?
几点钟了？
So if I use my find my extract min algorithm before,
因此，如果我以前使用自己的提取最小算法，
what was the running time?
几点钟了？
AUDIENCE: It was [INAUDIBLE].
听众：是[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So it's not the--
教授：所以不是……
AUDIENCE: Oh sorry it's the--
听众：抱歉，
PROFESSOR: So what's one operation in a heap?
教授：那么堆中的一个操作是什么？
If I have the height of a heap, what's an operation?
如果我有堆高，那是什么操作？
How much time does it take to do one operation
一次操作需要多少时间
as a function of the height of the heap?
是堆高的函数吗？
So if my heap has h levels, in this case
因此，如果我的堆具有h级，在这种情况下
h happens to be log N, it's order h.
h恰好是log N，顺序为h。
So if I reduce it-- I'm not reducing it from N to K.
因此，如果我减少它，我不会将其从N减少到K。
I wish I could.
我希望我能够。
I'm reducing it from log N to K.
我将其从log N减少到K。
So for really tiny K's, this becomes order K.
因此，对于非常小的K，这将变成阶K。
And my total running time is K squared.
我的总运行时间是K平方。
So I'm going to do K operations, K extract mins.
所以我要进行K次运算，K次提取分钟。
OK now the reason I wanted to entertain this is I
好吧，我想要娱乐的原因是我
claim it's going to be useful to help us find the answer.
声称这将有助于我们找到答案。
So everything that we have here gives us some insight
因此，我们这里拥有的一切都给我们一些见识
into what the correct answer is.
正确答案是什么。
Well what our correct answer is.
好吧，我们的正确答案是。
There might be others.
可能还有其他。
So let's think for a bit, and see if we can do better.
因此，让我们考虑一下，看看我们是否可以做得更好。
Am I covering something?
我覆盖了什么吗？
I hope not.
我希望不是。
So by the way, when you have problems on your own,
顺便说一句，当您自己遇到问题时，
say you are looking at CLRS or at old exams,
说您正在看CLRS或旧考试，
you want to give yourselves half an hour, an hour to think.
你想给自己半个小时，一个小时的思考时间。
And just this process alone is going
仅此过程就在进行
to help you do better on a test.
帮助您在测试中做得更好。
Because while you're thinking you're going through everything
因为当你以为自己正在经历一切
you know.
你懂。
And you're rearranging stuff in your brain
而且您正在重新整理大脑中的内容
in a way that will be easier to access it later.
以一种以后可以更轻松地访问它的方式。
So now you're going to think, what do I know about heaps?
所以现在您要考虑，我对堆有什么了解？
What do I know that takes log N time?
我怎么知道需要N倍的时间？
What do I know that takes N log N time?
我怎么知道需要N log N时间？
And your brain will be better at answering
而且你的大脑会更好地回答
these kinds of questions later.
这些问题以后。
Now we're not going to give you 30 minutes,
现在我们不会给您30分钟，
because that would make us run out of time.
因为那会使我们用尽时间。
AUDIENCE: You want to reduce it down to K elements.
听众：您希望将其减少到K个元素。
PROFESSOR: I want to only have to look
教授：我只想看看
at K elements, that's good.
在K个元素上，那很好。
AUDIENCE: Otherwise you can't plug K into the search.
听众：否则您无法将K插入搜索。
PROFESSOR: Yep, OK so that's good.
教授：是的，很好。
AUDIENCE: Which is interesting, because it's K log K,
观众：这很有趣，因为它是K log K，
and that kind of suggests that you'd
那种暗示你会
have K elements in the tree.
树中有K个元素。
But then you're searching for each one in the tree.
但是，然后您正在树中搜索每个。
PROFESSOR: So maybe I'm not going
教授：所以也许我不去
to be able to cut this heap into K elements, right?
可以将堆切成K个元素，对吗？
I'll have to do a bit more.
我还要做更多。
AUDIENCE: Can you cut this heap into K elements
听众：您可以将此堆切成K个元素吗？
and use that heap to do our [INAUDIBLE]?
并用那个堆做我们的[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: Let's see how we'd cut this heap.
教授：让我们看看如何削减这个堆。
First off let's see how this keep
首先，让我们看看如何保持
would look like if it's cut.
看起来好像被切掉了。
How do we find the first K elements here?
我们如何在这里找到前K个元素？
How do we find the first element?
我们如何找到第一个元素？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: It's the root.
教授：这是根源。
Second element.
第二要素。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: What do I look at?
教授：我怎么看？
If I want to select the second element in a heap,
如果我要选择堆中的第二个元素，
how many elements do I have to look at?
我必须看几个元素？
Two, 5 and 7, because everything below will be bigger, right?
二，五和七，因为下面的所有内容都会更大，对吧？
OK I look at them, I compare them,
好吧，我看着它们，我比较它们，
I know 5 is the smallest one.
我知道5是最小的。
Now suppose I want to find the third element.
现在假设我要查找第三个元素。
Who do I look at?
我看谁？
7 or the thing under 5.
7或5岁以下的事物。
So 7 is still in the race for sure.
所以肯定7仍然在比赛中。
And then I have to look at the children of 5.
然后我要看看5岁的孩子。
Right now we're looking at 3.
目前，我们正在研究3。
Suppose this has some really large kids.
假设这个孩子很大。
As in numbers.
如数字。
And I find that this is the third element.
我发现这是第三个要素。
Who do I look at for the fourth element?
我应该看谁的第四个要素？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK so this isn't in the race
教授：好的，所以这不在比赛中
anymore, because it's the third.
不再，因为它是第三。
The fourth has to be either of these two guys.
第四个必须是这两个家伙中的一个。
Or the kids here, right?
还是这里的孩子，对吗？
And it happens to be 7.
恰好是7。
So I take it out.
所以我把它拿出来。
If I want to look at the-- if I want to find the next element,
如果要查看-如果要查找下一个元素，
who's in the race?
谁在比赛？
This guy gets out of the race.
这个家伙不参加比赛。
AUDIENCE: 7's kids.
观众：7个孩子。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK so we have something.
教授：好的，我们有东西。
We're not really cutting up the heap,
我们并没有真正削减堆，
but we are sort of computing where the blade would
但是我们正在计算刀片将在哪里
go if we wanted to cut it up in K elements and N minus K
如果我们想将其切成K个元素和N减去K
elements.
元素。
Does this make some sense?
这有意义吗？
Nods, no nods.
点头，点头。
AUDIENCE: I mean I guess you're never
听众：我的意思是我猜你永远不会
going to be going down farther than K.
比K下降得更远。
PROFESSOR: So let's just understand the concept.
教授：所以让我们来了解一下这个概念。
And then we're going to do one more pass,
然后我们要再做一遍
write pseudocode, and understand the running time.
编写伪代码，并了解运行时间。
Because this is still confusing, right?
因为这仍然令人困惑，对吗？
We'll need one more pass, otherwise
我们需要再过一遍，否则
we can't write the pseudocode into it.
我们无法将伪代码写入其中。
So does the concept make sense?
那么这个概念有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: Is that K log K?
听众：那是K log K吗？
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
So the idea here is that I have a horizon that says,
所以这里的想法是，我有一个地平线，说，
what are the next elements that I'm willing to consider?
我愿意考虑的下一个要素是什么？
And first the horizon starts with just the root,
首先，视野始于根源
because I know that's the minimum element.
因为我知道这是最小的要素。
And when I take an element out of the horizon
当我把一个元素脱颖而出时
I put in its children.
我放了它的孩子们。
That's what I did all the time.
那就是我一直在做的事。
So given a horizon how do I know what the next elements
所以给定一个视野，我怎么知道接下来的内容
to extract out of the horizon?
拔出地平线？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: The mean, OK.
教授：卑鄙的，好的。
So I want a data structure for the horizon
所以我想要一个数据结构
that can extract means quickly.
可以快速提取出平均值。
OK what am I going to use for the horizon?
好吧，我将用于地平线吗？
A min heap, excellent.
小堆，好极了。
So let's try to go for pseudocode.
因此，让我们尝试使用伪代码。
Suppose we have H as our original heap.
假设我们有H作为原始堆。
So H is a mean heap.
所以H是一个平均堆。
We will make Z be our horizon.
我们将Z作为我们的视野。
I can't use H again.
我不能再使用H。
It would be nice if I could, but I'll
如果可以的话会很好，但是我会
use Z because Z's also a letter in horizon.
使用Z，因为Z也是水平字母。
So Z's the mean heap.
所以Z是平均堆。
And then first I will insert into Z.
然后首先我将插入Z。
I'll insert the heap's root, right?
我将插入堆的根，对吗？
So Z dot insert H of 1.
因此Z点插入H为1。
Remember that heaps are actually arrays.
请记住，堆实际上是数组。
I hinted to his earlier.
我向他暗示过。
So these nodes have are elements in an array.
因此，这些节点具有数组中的元素。
So this is the first element, second, third, fourth, fifth,
这是第一要素，第二，第三，第四，第五，
sixth.
第六。
So we're using array backed heaps, and H of one
所以我们使用的是数组支持的堆
is going to be the root.
将成为根。
Then I'm going to compute the first K elements like this,
然后，我将像这样计算前K个元素，
for K in range-- sorry, for i in range K,
对于范围内的K-对不起，对于范围内K的我，
so K is going to go from 1 to K.
所以K将从1到K
What I want to do?
我想做的事？
Take, compute the ith element.
以计算第ith个元素为例。
How do I do that?
我怎么做？
AUDIENCE: Extract min.
观众：提取分钟。
PROFESSOR: i equals Z dot extract min.
教授：我等于Z点提取最小值。
And then I want to insert the children in the horizon.
然后，我想将孩子们插入地平线。
Right?
对？
How do I do that?
我怎么做？
AUDIENCE: 2i and 2i plus 1.
听众：2i和2i加1。
PROFESSOR: OK so this is if I know the index, right?
教授：好的，如果我知道索引，对吗？
When I'm putting things in the heap
当我把东西放在堆里
the keys are going to be the values,
键将是值，
so that I can take out the minimum.
这样我就可以拿出最少的钱。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] heap first and then inserted H Y.
听众：先[堆]，然后插入HY。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, OK.
教授：是的，好的。
This is empty.
这是空的。
And this is the input.
这就是输入。
OK so I need to use the numbers as the keys.
确定，所以我需要使用数字作为键。
So when I extract something out of the heap,
所以当我从堆中提取东西时，
so when I extract the first element it's going to say 2,
因此，当我提取第一个元素时，它将说2，
it's not going to say 1.
它不会说1。
If I want to--
如果我想 -
AUDIENCE: Why wouldn't Z dot extract [INAUDIBLE] because--
听众：为什么Z点不能提取[听不清]，因为-
PROFESSOR: So this will give me the next key in the horizon.
教授：因此，这将给我带来下一个关键。
AUDIENCE: But-- oh I see, you're starting out
听众：但是-哦，我明白了，你正在开始
with just the first one.
与第一个。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Oh and then you want to add in the next.
听众：哦，然后您想添加下一个。
PROFESSOR: So at the end of this whole thing,
教授：所以到此为止，
if I'm extracting them right, I can return this variable here.
如果我正确地提取它们，则可以在此处返回此变量。
Because after K durations this is going to be the Kth element.
因为在K个持续时间之后，这将成为第K个元素。
So I return it and I'm done.
因此，我将其退回并完成。
The problem is I want this guy's index too, right?
问题是我也想要这个人的索引，对吗？
So I can't just store the key in the heap.
所以我不能只将密钥存储在堆中。
I have to augment the heap to let me store values.
我必须增加堆容量才能存储值。
And I have to store the index.
而且我必须存储索引。
So for this guy would have Z insert H of 1,
因此，对于这个人，将Z插入为1的H
and then it's index 1.
然后是索引1。
Then when I get out the ith element
然后当我得到第i个元素时
I'll also get out it's index.
我也会弄清楚它的索引。
A variable name for that?
那是一个变量名吗？
AUDIENCE: j.
听众：j。
PROFESSOR: j.
教授：j。
OK why would you name your variables like this?
OK，为什么要这样命名变量？
In the previous section I had a similar suggestion, i, i.
在上一节中，我有一个类似的建议。
So why would you name your variables like this?
那么，为什么要这样命名变量？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Job security.
教授：工作安全。
All right.
好吧。
So it's OK here.
所以在这里还可以。
Try to not to do that when doing an exam or an interview,
考试或面试时尽量不要这样做，
because it reflects poorly on you.
因为它对您的反映很差。
For an interview and for an exam you'll get us upset
进行面试和考试会让我们不高兴
and we might be less lenient.
而且我们可能不那么宽容。
Or at least explain what you're doing.
或者至少说明您在做什么。
So extract min is going to give us the key.
所以摘录分钟将给我们关键。
And it's going to give us index in the heap.
这将为我们提供堆中的索引。
What do we do afterwards?
之后我们该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: We add to [INAUDIBLE] H of--
观众：我们在[听不清]的H中加上-
PROFESSOR: All right so when we take out 2--
教授：好的，所以当我们取出2--
so we start out with an horizon of 2.
所以我们从2开始
When we take it out 2's the only thing that's in the horizon
当我们取出2时，唯一出现的就是
first.
第一。
Then we take it out and its two children get in the horizon.
然后我们将其取出，它的两个孩子进入了视野。
Then we take out one of the children
然后我们带出一个孩子
and put its children in the horizon.
并把它的孩子放在地平线上。
So when we take out a node we want
所以当我们取出一个节点时
to put its children in the horizon.
把孩子放到地平线上
So we're going to say Z dot--
所以我们要说Z点
AUDIENCE: Insert.
听众：插入。
PROFESSOR: Insert.
教授：插入。
What do I insert?
我要插入什么？
AUDIENCE: H of I times 2.
听众：我的H乘以2。
j times 2.
j次2。
PROFESSOR: See?
教授：看到了吗？
It's working already.
它已经在工作了。
The job security thing is working.
工作安全的东西正在工作。
And?
和？
AUDIENCE: 2j plus 1.
听众：2j加1。
You have to do two lines.
您必须做两行。
PROFESSOR: OK, sweet.
教授：好，甜。
OK.
好。
Does this work?
这样行吗？
I mean does this do what we wanted it to do earlier?
我的意思是，这是否可以做我们希望它做的事？
AUDIENCE: Wait, we're extracting oh--
听众：等等，我们正在提取哦-
PROFESSOR: All right first nod.
教授：好的，首先点头。
AUDIENCE: I mean if K is small enough.
听众：我的意思是说K是否足够小。
Eventually you'll ask for something that is out of range.
最终，您会要求超出范围的东西。
PROFESSOR: Oh so you're thinking that eventually these
教授：哦，你在想，最终这些
will run out of range.
将超出范围。
AUDIENCE: If you have your really lopsided array
听众：如果您的阵列确实偏斜
eventually you'll ask for something that's [INAUDIBLE].
最终，您会要求提供[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: OK what would we want to do in that case?
教授：好的，在这种情况下我们想做什么？
AUDIENCE: Just want to check to make sure that the [INAUDIBLE].
听众：只想检查一下以确保[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, but otherwise move on, right?
教授：是的，但否则继续吧？
If an element doesn't have kids, we don't add on to the horizon.
如果某个元素没有孩子，那么我们就不会增加视野。
So we need some bounce checks, exception checking,
因此，我们需要一些反弹检查，异常检查，
things like that in here.
这样的事情在这里。
And I won't add that because that
我不会添加，因为那样
will make it look long and ugly.
会使它看起来又长又丑。
So this is the idea.
所以这就是主意。
OK what's the running time for this?
好的，这是什么时间？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
So creating heaps, initializing, all order 1, insertion,
因此，创建堆，初始化所有顺序1，插入，
this heap is almost empty now.
现在这个堆几乎是空的。
So this is order 1.
所以这是命令1。
Then these happen K times.
然后这些发生K次。
And these are all operations on the heap Z.
这些都是对堆Z的操作。
And the heap for the heap Z, it has some number of elements.
而对于Z堆来说，它具有一定数量的元素。
And it's not always going to have one element,
而且并不总是只有一个要素，
because every time I'm extracting
因为每次我提取
one element I'm adding two.
一个元素，我要添加两个。
So well how many elements is it going to have at most?
那么，它最多将包含多少个元素？
AUDIENCE: K.
观众：K.
PROFESSOR: OK why is that?
教授：那为什么呢？
AUDIENCE: Because each time you add it it's one element.
听众：因为每次添加它都是一个要素。
PROFESSOR: So I extract one for sure.
教授：所以我确定要摘一个。
And then I add at most two elements.
然后，我最多添加两个元素。
So the heap size grows by at most 1 in every iteration.
因此，每次迭代堆大小最多增加1。
So the heap size Z will have at most K elements.
因此，堆大小Z将最多具有K个元素。
So now I know the running for all these operations.
所以现在我知道所有这些操作的运行情况。
What is it?
它是什么？
Log K. Cool.
日志K。
So it's K times log K. And the reason that it works,
所以它是K乘以logK。它起作用的原因是，
it's a bit harder to see.
很难看。
You have to convince yourself maybe using this bigger tree,
您必须说服自己也许使用这棵更大的树，
that whenever you're spending expanding the horizon
无论何时，只要您花钱扩大视野
you're expanding it the right way.
您正在以正确的方式扩展它。
So the idea is again that whatever
所以想法再次是
path you take down you're going to see ascending numbers.
您沿路径走下去，您将看到升序的数字。
So when you're increasing the horizon
因此，当您扩大视野时
you're always pushing it down in such a way
你总是以这种方式推低它
that your invariant is that all the numbers in the horizon
你不变的是地平线上的所有数字
are smaller then their children.
比他们的孩子小。
And so on and so forth.
等等等等。
So the horizon is always guaranteed
因此，视野始终得到保证
to have the smallest number that you haven't extracted yet.
拥有您尚未提取的最小号码。
And that's really the only thing you need.
这确实是您唯一需要的。
OK does this make some sense?
好的，这有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: It never would have occurred to me on an exam.
听众：我从来没有想过要考试。
PROFESSOR: Yeah exactly.
教授：是的。
This would not occur on an exam unless you think a lot,
除非您考虑很多，否则考试不会发生这种情况，
you're super inspired, all that.
所有这些，您超级有启发。
If it doesn't occur to you what do you do?
如果您没有想到该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Go with the N log K solution.
听众：选择N log K解决方案。
PROFESSOR: OK, very good.
教授：好的，很好。
Wait.
等待。
AUDIENCE: K log N.
听众：K logN。
PROFESSOR: OK, K log N or N log K, which one?
教授：好的，K log N或N log K，哪个？
AUDIENCE: K log N.
听众：K logN。
PROFESSOR: Why?
教授：为什么？
Two reasons.
有两个原因。
K log N is-- so two reasons, faster and simpler.
K log N是-因此有两个原因，更快和更简单。
So you write this down.
所以你写下来。
And you get half score or 3/4 of the score and you're done.
然后您得到一半的分数或分数的3/4，您就完成了。
It's better than nothing, anything,
总比没有好，
and getting a 0, right?
并得到0，对吗？
I mean 3/4 of a score for two lines of pseudocode
我的意思是两行伪代码的3/4分
is reasonable, right?
是合理的吧？
Two or three lines.
两三行。
This is three lines probably.
这大概是三行。
Also on most exams we're humans, right?
而且在大多数考试中我们都是人类，对吗？
We might mess them up, we might make them too long.
我们可能将它们弄乱，我们可能会使它们太长。
If we make them too long, you want
如果我们让它们太长，你想要
to get the most number of points.
获得最多的积分。
You'll have time to figure out one or two
您将有时间找出一两个
problems at that level.
该级别的问题。
But if we give you too many, for the rest of them
但是如果我们给您太多，其余的
you want to have something simple that
您想拥有一些简单的东西
gives you some of the points.
给你一些要点。
Same for an interview.
采访也一样。
For most interviews most people don't really
对于大多数采访，大多数人并没有真正
have a clue how many problems you can solve,
了解您可以解决多少问题，
how many problems are reasonable.
有多少问题是合理的。
So you want, for every problem you
所以你想要，对于每个问题
want to show some solution reasonably fast.
希望尽快显示一些解决方案。
And then see if they're happy.
然后看看他们是否幸福。
And if they're happy move on to the next problem.
如果他们愿意，请继续解决下一个问题。
And if they're not happy only then spend more time.
如果他们不开心，那就花更多的时间。
So this is as important as that.
因此，这一点同样重要。
If you look at the recitation notes we'll have some problems
如果您看一下朗诵笔记，我们会遇到一些问题
and we'll have some solutions.
我们将提供一些解决方案。
What are going to do, memorize the solutions?
该怎么做，记住解决方案？
Yay, you know how to solve more problems.
是的，您知道如何解决更多问题。
There are probably a million problems in total.
总共可能存在一百万个问题。
That doesn't get you very far.
这不会使您走得太远。
So what you want is to understand this process
所以你想要的是了解这个过程
that we went through.
我们经历的。
So every time we tried something we got from some point
所以每次我们尝试从某个角度得到的东西
to some point with a better running time.
在某种程度上具有更好的运行时间。
Well except for here.
好吧，除了这里。
And where we had more insight on the problem.
我们对这个问题有更多的见识。
So this is the important part.
因此，这是重要的部分。
And I'm going to show you one more problem, really quickly.
我将很快向您展示另一个问题。
We're probably not going to be able to solve it,
我们可能无法解决它，
because it's hard.
因为很难
But we are going to talk about it
但是我们要谈论它
and see if we can get some insight.
看看我们能否获得一些见识。
Let's see, what do I want to erase?
让我们看看，我要删除什么？
This.
这个。
I like that.
我喜欢。
All right, so we have an array random numbers, 7, 2, 5--
好吧，所以我们有一个数组随机数7、2、5
this time there's no order in it-- 8, 9, 4.
这次没有顺序-8、9、4
And we tell you that the array has 2 to the N numbers,
我们告诉你，数组有2到N个数字，
to make the problem easier.
使问题变得更容易。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
1、2、3、4、5、6、7
6.
6。
So you have this array.
所以你有这个数组。
And we want to answer queries of this shape.
我们想回答这种形状的查询。
Say this array is E, and it has N elements,
假设此数组为E，并且包含N个元素，
and you know that N is some 2 to the K.
而且您知道N比K大2
Minimum of all the elements from i to j.
从i到j的所有元素中的最小值。
So you have two phases, just like we
所以您有两个阶段，就像我们
had on a problem on the exam.
考试有问题。
You have a pre-processing stage where you get the array,
您有一个预处理阶段，可以获取阵列，
you do some computation, you save some information.
您进行一些计算，就可以保存一些信息。
And then you have a querying phase,
然后进入查询阶段
where you have to answer these as fast as possible.
您必须尽快回答这些问题。
I see most people have unhappy faces.
我看到大多数人都有不高兴的面孔。
Bad memories, huh?
不好的回忆，是吗？
OK let's not worry about that problem.
好吧，我们不用担心这个问题。
Let's look at this one.
让我们来看看这个。
So assuming you have as much time as you
所以假设你有很多时间
want to do the pre-processing, what's
想进行预处理，这是什么
the fastest way you could answer these?
您回答这些问题的最快方法？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: If you had as much time
观众：如果您有很多时间
for pre-processing [INAUDIBLE] memorize it.
用于预处理[音频不清晰]记住它。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So if we compute the answers to all possible solutions, right?
因此，如果我们计算所有可能解决方案的答案，对吗？
How would I store that?
我将如何存储？
So I want to do this in order 1.
所以我想按顺序进行1。
So how would I store these answers?
那么我将如何存储这些答案？
AUDIENCE: Just sort your array.
听众：对数组进行排序。
PROFESSOR: OK so I sort my array.
教授：好的，所以我对数组进行排序。
AUDIENCE: Then you want the minimum from i to j,
听众：那么你想要从i到j的最小值，
so look at the ith element and that's your [INAUDIBLE].
因此，请看第ith个元素，这就是您的[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: OK so figure it out?
教授：好，知道了吗？
Well I mean if I can sort it I can also say hey,
好吧，我的意思是，如果我可以对它进行排序，我也可以说，
why don't we use this array instead?
为什么我们不使用这个数组呢？
And then I'll answer the queries.
然后我将回答查询。
You can go off a tangent trying to sort the elements
您可以切线尝试对元素进行排序
and keep their keys.
并保持他们的钥匙。
The important thing is if you think about it for awhile
重要的是如果您考虑一会儿
and you see that things stop making sense, back out.
然后您会发现事情不再有意义，请退出。
Look somewhere else.
看其他地方
We spent some time trying to find a solution based
我们花了一些时间试图找到一个基于
on sorting in my last section.
在上一节中进行排序。
It's not going to work.
这是行不通的。
So--
所以 -
AUDIENCE: Can't you just take the [INAUDIBLE] from i to j?
听众：难道你不能把[听不清]从i转移到j吗？
PROFESSOR: OK let's get to that in a bit.
教授：好吧，让我们稍作讨论。
So let's keep that in mind.
因此，请记住这一点。
Because that's another point on the trade off curve.
因为那是折衷曲线上的另一点。
So if I want to serve my queries in order 1,
因此，如果我想按顺序投放查询1，
then the way I do that is I will have a hash of all the arrays
那么我这样做的方式是我将拥有所有数组的哈希
that look like i, j.
看起来像我，j。
So all the possible intervals.
所以所有可能的间隔。
And I'll store the answer here.
我将答案存储在这里。
The minimum the elements from i to j.
从i到j的最小元素。
And I can do a hash lookup in order 1 and get the answer
我可以按顺序1进行哈希查找并得到答案
and return the answer.
然后返回答案。
How many elements so I have here?
我在这里有多少个元素？
So how much storage do I have to use for this?
那么，我必须为此使用多少存储空间？
AUDIENCE: O of N squared.
听众：N的O平方。
PROFESSOR: OK N values for this, N values for this, so roughly
教授：可以的，N个值，大概N个值
N squared.
N平方。
What's the time for computing this?
什么时候计算这个？
Brute force, let's not think.
蛮力，别想。
What's the time for computing this?
什么时候计算这个？
AUDIENCE: N cubed.
听众：N立方。
PROFESSOR: N cubed.
教授：N立方。
You're thinking.
你在想
So I have unsquared elements here.
所以我这里有未平方的元素。
For every element I have to compute
对于我必须计算的每个元素
the minimum of potentially order N elements, right?
潜在的N个元素的最小值，对不对？
So this is N cubed.
所以这是N立方的。
I could reduce it to N squared by noticing that if I have
我可以注意一下，如果有
the minimum of these elements, and I
这些元素中的最小值，我
want to compute the minimum of these elements,
想要计算这些元素中的最小值，
really all I have to do is compute, compare
我要做的就是计算，比较
this minimum with this element.
此元素的最小值。
So every time I start with an interval of size 1
所以每次我以1个间隔开始
and then I expand it by 1.
然后将其扩展1。
So I have my two for loops here.
所以我在这里有两个for循环。
And I keep growing my minimum.
而且我不断提高自己的最低要求。
So I could get down to order of N squared times.
所以我可以下降到N平方次的量级。
So I have one solution that has order
所以我有一个有订单的解决方案
of N squared time and space, and then answers
N的时间和空间的平方，然后回答
the queries in order 1.
查询顺序1。
You had a solution you said where, what you do
您有一个解决方案，您说过在哪里做什么
is, when you get a query you compute this, right?
是，当您获得查询时，您会对此进行计算，对吗？
You were suggesting sorting the array.
您建议对数组进行排序。
That would be N log N. I would suggest not sorting it.
那将是N logN。我建议不要对其进行排序。
Do the splicing, you look through all the elements,
进行拼接，您会浏览所有元素，
and you find the minimum.
然后找到最低要求。
AUDIENCE: I was saying that if the original E spans i to j
听众：我是说如果原始E跨越i到j
and started at the--
并开始于
PROFESSOR: So when you get a query the i's
教授：所以当您查询时
and j's change for every query.
每个查询的j的变化。
Otherwise we could compute the answer.
否则我们可以计算答案。
So we have one answer where we take order
所以我们有一个答案来点菜
N time to answer a query.
N次回答查询。
And what do we do for pre-processing?
那我们要做什么预处理呢？
Nothing.
没有。
Order 1.
顺序1。
So these are two ends of a trade off, right?
所以这是权衡的两个目的，对吗？
One possible extreme is that you pre-compute all your answers.
一种可能的极端情况是您预先计算了所有答案。
The other possible extreme is that you don't do anything
另一个可能的极端情况是您什么都不做
and you brute force every answer.
而您会蛮力地回答每个答案。
And now we want to find a point somewhere
现在我们想在某处找到一个点
on this line between the extremes.
在极端之间的这条线上。
So the answer that we're going to show in the solutions
所以我们将在解决方案中显示答案
uses order N log N space.
使用N阶N log N空间。
And it answers the query by using
并通过使用回答查询
order 1 elements in this order N log N data structure.
顺序1个元素，此顺序为N log N数据结构。
So I have order N log N partial minima.
因此，我有N个log N个局部最小值。
And I will only use two of them.
我将只使用其中两个。
So the total running time isn't actually order 1.
因此，总运行时间实际上不是1。
But we only use order 1 elements.
但是我们仅使用订单1元素。
Let's start thinking very quickly.
让我们开始快速思考。
Let's think for about a minute, and then we'll
让我们思考一分钟，然后
go through the solution.
通过解决方案。
And there are multiple solutions.
并且有多种解决方案。
All of them are interesting in different ways.
所有这些都以不同的方式引起人们的兴趣。
And there are other solutions that
还有其他解决方案
are equally fun and applicable with not the same running time.
同样有趣，并且适用于不同的运行时间。
Let me make some space here.
让我在这里留一些空间。
So like I said, thinking is a useful process on its own.
因此，就像我说的那样，思考本身就是一个有用的过程。
So you're getting better just by doing this.
因此，通过这样做，您会变得更好。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] using more than one space total?
听众：[听不清]总共使用了一个以上的空格？
PROFESSOR: We're using N log N space.
教授：我们正在使用N log N个空间。
AUDIENCE: Oh and it takes constant time--
听众：哦，这需要持续的时间-
PROFESSOR: It will only look at two elements.
教授：它只会看两个要素。
It's actually not constant time.
实际上，这不是固定时间。
We're not going to worry too much about time.
我们不会太担心时间。
It turns out being log.
原来是日志。
AUDIENCE: Ok, what was the order 1 then?
听众：好的，那第1阶是什么？
PROFESSOR: You only access order 1 elements.
教授：您只能访问订单1元素。
Order 1 partial minimum.
最少订购1个。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
Does it have to do with two different K?
它与两个不同的K有关吗？
PROFESSOR: Maybe.
教授：也许吧。
AUDIENCE: I don't know what to do with that.
听众：我不知道该怎么办。
There's probably some sort of tree involved.
可能涉及某种树。
PROFESSOR: So you're going to want to split things, right?
教授：那么您将要拆分内容，对吗？
Into halves.
分成两半。
And you're going to want to be able to do this all the time.
您将一直希望能够做到这一点。
And we say 2 to the K so we don't have to worry about,
我们对K说2，所以我们不必担心，
oh my God what happens if the halves aren't equal?
哦，天哪，如果两半不相等会怎样？
You can usually solve this when you implement the problem.
解决问题时，通常可以解决此问题。
But it's useful to not worry about
但是不用担心是很有用的
that when you come up with your first algorithm.
当你想出第一个算法时
If you're going to start dividing in halves.
如果您要开始分成两半。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Um.
教授：嗯。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So that leads to another useful solution.
教授：因此，这导致了另一个有用的解决方案。
That leads to a solution that takes-- that has N log N
这导致解决方案采用-N log N
storage and it will run in N log N time
存储，它将在N log N次后运行
with N log N element axes.
N个N个N个元素轴。
So what you thinking of is you're
所以你想的是
going to have your array of elements, right?
会有你的元素数组，对不对？
And say you want to find the minimum from here to here.
并说您想找到从此处到此处的最小值。
You're going to have your array split in half.
您将把阵列分成两半。
So you're going to find the minimum of this,
因此，您将找到其中的最小值，
and the minimum of this.
和最小的。
But to do that you'll have to recurse.
但是要做到这一点，您必须递归。
So this is also say split in half.
所以这也说成两半。
So you'll have to find-- so it turns out
所以您必须找到-事实证明
that if you do this, in the end you'll
如果您这样做，最终您将
have log N minima that you have to look at.
有必须查看的log N最小值。
But this is more, this is a cooler and more useful thing,
不仅如此，这是一个更酷，更有用的东西，
so I'll try to put it on a PSet or something
所以我会尝试把它放在PSet之类的东西上
to make you think about it.
让你考虑一下。
So this is-- don't tell people yet.
所以，这是-不要告诉别人。
You might have a solution to a problem.
您可能有解决问题的方法。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So what we thought of, or the way we thought of doing it,
因此，我们的想法或想法
is 6, 7, 2, 5, 3, 8, 9, 4.
是6、7、2、5、3、8、9、4。
So we compute these partial minima.
因此，我们计算了这些局部最小值。
We split the array into two.
我们将数组分成两部分。
And these are the minima that we compute.
这些是我们计算的最小值。
Sorry, this is like this, this is like this.
对不起，这是这样，这是这样。
So everything, so all the left half then these guys,
所以一切，剩下的这些家伙，
then these guys, then this guy.
然后是这些家伙，然后是这个家伙。
Everything here, then these guys, then these guys,
这里的一切，然后是这些人，然后是这些人，
then this guy.
然后这个家伙。
So if your i and j are on different sides of the middle,
因此，如果您的i和j位于中间位置的不同侧，
then you do two lookups, you're done.
然后您进行两次查找，就完成了。
If they're in the same half, then you
如果他们在同一半，那么你
have a problem that's half the size.
有一半的问题。
So you're going to have to take this array that's
因此，您将不得不采用该数组
half the size, 2, 5.
一半的尺寸2、5
Split it into halves and do the same thing.
将其分成两半，然后做同样的事情。
And then we're going to have to do the same to this other one.
然后，我们将不得不对另一个人做同样的事情。
3, 8, 9, 4, split it into halves and do the same thing.
3、8、9、4，将其分成两半，然后做同样的事情。
So in the end you'll end up in someplace
所以最后你会到某个地方
where your interval ages are on different sides of the middle.
您的间隔年龄在中间的不同侧。
And you look at two elements and you're done.
您看了两个元素，就完成了。
Let's see how much space this takes.
让我们看看这需要多少空间。
Can someone tell me a recursion for how much
有人可以告诉我递归多少
space, for how many minimums I would need to keep?
空间，我需要保持几个最小值？
So space for an elements is?
那么元素的空间是？
AUDIENCE: The first level you have 8.
听众：您的第一个级别是8。
So go down by an order of 2.
因此，按2的顺序下降。
PROFESSOR: So what's the first level?
教授：那么第一级是什么？
AUDIENCE: Of 8 N.
听众：8N。
PROFESSOR: So order N plus?
教授：那么订购N加？
AUDIENCE: N over 2?
听众：N大于2？
t of N over 2?
N大于2的t？
PROFESSOR: OK S because it's space.
教授：好的，因为它有空间。
N over 2.
N大于2。
OK.
好。
And?
和？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: You're missing something.
教授：您正在丢失一些东西。
Look at this picture.
看这张图片。
So this is the whole thing.
这就是全部。
Then I have a half.
然后我有一半。
And then what else do I have?
然后我还有什么？
AUDIENCE: 2.
听众：2。
PROFESSOR: The other half.
教授：另一半。
AUDIENCE: Oh, 2.
听众：哦，2。
PROFESSOR: OK so the difference between these two
教授：好的，所以两者之间的区别
is that one of them gives you order N,
是其中之一给您订单N，
the other one gives you N log N. So I gave you the answer,
另一个给你N logN。所以我给你答案，
so I can't ask you for the answer now.
所以我现在不能问你答案。
But where did we see this before?
但是我们以前在哪里看到的呢？
Pretend these are t's.
假设这些是t。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
So these are t's, this is the recursion for [? more sort ?].
这些是t，这是[？的递归更多排序？]。
So once you put it up you don't draw the recursion tree
因此，一旦您放上它，就不会绘制递归树
and solve it.
并解决它。
You say this is what we saw in [? more sort. ?] Therefore,
您说的就是我们在[？更多排序。 ？]因此，
the solution is N log N. So this is
解决方案是N logN。所以这是
how you show you have N log N space,
如何显示您有N log N个空间，
and it's pretty clear that you're only
很明显，你只是
going to access two elements.
要访问两个元素。
AUDIENCE: I don't understand how [INAUDIBLE].
听众：我不明白[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: How it works?
教授：如何运作？
So you have your i and you have your j.
所以你有你的i，你有j。
Let's make that one i here.
让我在这里做一个。
If you want to find the minimum, if i and j
如果要找到最小值，则i和j
are on different sides of the half, you have this and this.
在一半的不同侧面上，您拥有这个和这个。
And these two partial minima cover your entire interval.
这两个局部最小值覆盖了您的整个时间间隔。
Now if they're on the same side of the half then
现在，如果它们在一半的同一侧，
you recurse to a smaller problem.
您递归到一个较小的问题。
AUDIENCE: Well you don't have to there because you already
听众：嗯，您不必去那里，因为您已经
have the minimum of that section.
具有该部分的最小值。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: It wouldn't work if you had 6 and 2, right?
听众：如果您有6和2，那是行不通的，对吗？
Or that.
或者那个。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Well why not just take 7 and 2 then?
听众：那么为什么不只拿7和2呢？
Why do you have to break up the entire panel?
为什么您必须分解整个面板？
PROFESSOR: Assume there's more things there.
教授：假设那里还有更多东西。
AUDIENCE: Oh I see.
听众：哦，我明白了。
PROFESSOR: So if you have this, now it's no longer true, right?
教授：所以，如果您有这个，现在不再适用，对吗？
So wherever they are here, you do that.
因此，无论他们在这里，您都可以这样做。
And remember your pseudocode has to be as simple as possible
并记住您的伪代码必须尽可能简单
to reduce the probability of bugs.
减少错误的可能性。
So you want to do the simplest possible thing,
所以您想做最简单的事情，
not have special cases.
没有特殊情况。
OK.
好。
By the way there's a study that shows
顺便说一下，有一项研究表明
that for good or bad programmers, if you have
无论好坏的程序员
1,000 lines of code, there's a constant probability of a bug.
1,000行代码，存在错误的可能性是恒定的。
And the constants are different for good
常量永远是不同的
versus bad programmers, but it's still a constant.
与糟糕的程序员相比，但这仍然是一个常数。
So how many mistakes you make is directly
所以你直接犯了多少错误
proportional to how much you write.
与你写多少成正比。
This is why we like simple solutions.
这就是为什么我们喜欢简单的解决方案。
OK, any questions on this?
好，对此有任何疑问吗？
So we have four problems.
因此，我们有四个问题。
We didn't cover one.
我们没有涵盖一个。
Look at the other one, look at the solution.
看另一个，看解决方案。
Ideally look at the problem, think for at least half
理想地看问题，至少思考一半
an hour, then look at the solution.
一个小时，然后看看解决方案。
What I want you to take away is not just oh, here
我要你带走的不只是哦，在这里
are three problems, let's memorize how we solve them.
是三个问题，让我们记住我们如何解决它们。
But the whole process thing, and how
但是整个过程，以及如何
we played with data structures and how we used all the hints
我们研究了数据结构以及如何使用所有提示
that we possibly could to build more insights into the problem.
我们可能可以对这个问题建立更多的见解。
OK, cool.
好的。